As I said earlier if you have certain types of pages you are going to have to treat them separately.
The most important of course is the clay coated shinny pages for books.
Usually this is in glossy books, picture books, if you have an art book chances are it is going to have, be clay coated.
If this is the case it is very important for you to put wax paper in between every single page.
If the pages are allowed to dry while they are touching they will fuse together into one mass.
So you just take regular wax paper and you are going to put it in between pages, you want to make sure that it is flat.
Now one of the problems that you are going to have once you put all of the paper in between the pages is that it is going to distort the book.
Unfortunately this can not be avoided.
Your choices are either having a distorted book with dry pages or a book in which you can't separate any of the pages because they have all dried together.
Of course if you want to use your book ever again, your best option is to have slightly distorted pages in order for you to be able to read them.
So you want to go through putting wax paper between every single page, now because they are clay coated these pages are going to be a lot stronger than regular book pages so you don't have to worry about them being quite as fragile while they are wet.
Once again, this is for the partially wet books.
You might need professional help if your book is completely saturated and it's the clay coated shinny pages.